Guide to the James Weldon Johnson Collection Manuscript Miscellany
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- W
  - WILSON, AUGUST
    - "Jitney", 2000 February 17; Wilson, August, 1945-2005; 1 item (111 p.); 29 cm. (Box GROUP 63, Folder F-1)
      Draft, typescript photocopy, corrected, of Wilson's script for the play Jitney. Includes a playbill from the 2000 May revival at the Penumbra Theatre in St. Paul, Minnesota.
      Accession: 2016-jwj-0008
  - WRIGHT, RICHARD, 1908-1960
    - "Leader Man: A Short Story", [ca. 1959]; Wright, Richard, 1908-1960; 1 item (96 leaves); 28 cm. (Box GROUP 28, Folder F-1)
      Draft, typescript, of unpublished short story. Inscription on cover: "Unpublished--sent to Constance Webb by Richard Wright."
      Accession: 9077
    - "Human Intelligence", undated; 1 item (1 p.); 23 cm. (Box GROUP 28, Folder F-2)
      Typescript, signed, responses to three questions regarding "Human Intelligence" written in an unidentified hand at the top of the manuscript. The three questions are: 1. Is human intelligence a unity, i.e./a complete whole in itself; 2. Is it possible for a man of genius to be as prominent in one disciplines as in another?; 3. Could a famous scientist who concentrates in a definite kind of research (or a famous writer who specializes in a certain type of literature), apply his intelligence to any field he would choose, successfully?
      Accession: 2012.jwj.23
      Purchased from David Schulson Autographs on the James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection of Negro Arts & Letters Fund, 2012.
    - Letter: to Henri Corbiere, 1946 September 26; Wright, Richard, 1908-1960; 1 item (1 p.); 29 cm. (Box GROUP 28, Folder F-3)
      Autograph letter, signed, to Henri Corbiere. The letter contains answers to questions about Wright's literary life posed by Corbiere. Corbiere's questions are written in his hand at the top of the page.
      Purchased from Schulson Autographs on the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 2016.
      Accession: 2016-jwj-0030